<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<AnnotatedDocument>
  <DocumentText>U3626939,6254_00054,2012-09-28,"ATTENDING ADDENDUM   
Ms. Ruby Tedford was seen as part of a shared Medical Oncology Clinic visit.  Please refer to Leslie Anderson's note above for further details.  She is 67-year-old woman who is a lifetime nonsmoker with a previous history of left breast cancer and had a left lower lobe adenocarcinoma which was presumed stage III and treated with lobectomy and subsequently postoperatively was found to have several small punctate lesions in the brain suspicious for brain metastases.

Ms. Tedford was seen by myself on September 19, 2012, in consultation.  At that time we had a very long discussion regarding whether adjuvant chemotherapy was needed versus whether we should consider watchful waiting, and Ms. Tedford has a lot of anxiety and stress and depression issues which were quite substantial and are currently being managed.  She is currently on antidepressant and is waiting for this to work.

Ms. Tedford was seen today outside her regular appointment.  She was booked to see me next week but as I had a phone call from pathology indicating that she had an L858R EGFR mutation, she is here to start Tarceva.  She does have a number of insurance difficulties and we are here to sort out the insurance forms as she has at least a 2,000 dollar co-pay and we are applying for patient assistance today with the aid of our pharmacist.  I have written her a prescription for Tarceva at 150 mg once daily, and I did perform a substantial amount of teaching regarding medications that she should take or should avoid, as well as that of grapefruit juice, and taking Tarceva on an empty stomach.  Other than this, she has had some Vicodin started for pain and cough by Leslie Anderson.  Ms. Tedford had a number of questions which I answered to her satisfaction today, as well as I also participated in some teaching, and we addressed the paperwork as well as her anxiety and issues with stress.  Overall, she is very pleased and happy to have had the EGFR mutation and is pleased to be starting on the Tarceva.  In regards to her brain lesions, she will follow up in most likely 6 to 7 weeks' time to see if these are responding to the Tarceva.  I would not advocate any obvious need for gamma knife or radiation therapy or whole-brain radiation at this time, and she is very pleased in regards to this.  I will inform Dr. Rockhill as well as Dr. Shilpen Patel.  Furthermore, I did indicate that we could start some antinauseants and minocycline or Imodium if needed, and I did start her on some minocycline as the patient felt more comfortable having this prescription just in case.  She will call us if she has any diarrhea or any other symptoms.

I did indicate that Tarceva can cause some liver enzyme rise and I will see her back in 2 weeks to check her laboratory work as well as her tolerability.  I did indicate that at any time if she has any major toxicities, she could stop this and we could always dose reduce her.  However, at this time she is motivated to proceed.  I did review with her also her radiology imaging that demonstrated no obvious evidence of any bone metastases nor is there any evidence of any systemic disease.  However, I did feel that it would be helpful, as Tarceva does go into the brain and there are responses in the brain, for her to proceed in a semi adjuvant or metastatic setting with the Tarceva which should have a good response.

I saw and assessed Ms. Ruby Tedford today in a face-to-face interaction.  I spent 15 minutes with her.  All of my time involved counseling and coordination of care and was in addition to the time spent by Leslie Anderson on September 28.

"
</DocumentText>
  <TextAnnotationSet/>
</AnnotatedDocument>
